(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T18:00:49.307595",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
魂の色は
What is the color of my soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"Just leave it broken as it is"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
To the point of throwing it away or running away
強くないよ ほら
I'm not that strong, see?
もう一度 鼓動、高鳴る
Once more, my heartbeat echoes high
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
Even if I don't know what's right or wrong...
形ののないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Only formless things become truly precious
飾らない言葉が 強く結ばれてる
Unadorned words are bound tightly together
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and falling again, yet still unbroken
魂の色は 何色ですか
What is the color of my soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, yet still wanting to find it
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm confirming the shape of my soul
深い地の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Alone in the deep depths of the earth, searching for a door and key
おとぎ話は ほら 泡の様に全部消えて
Look, fairy tales all vanish like bubbles,
葛藤 残像だけ 次の頁へ
leaving only conflicts and afterimages for the next page
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
Growing branches split apart, each walking their own path
寂しい思い出だけが 強く根を張ってる
Only lonely memories take deep roots
まだ貫いて 押し黙って それでも挫けない
Still piercing through, keeping silent, yet still undaunted
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて 抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind, slipping away, yet still wanting to convey it
魂の日々を 魂の意志を
The days of my soul, the will of my soul
ずっと
Forever...
魂の色は
What color is your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に 生きるあなたは
In a transparent past, an opaque tomorrow, what color do you live in?
何色ですか
What color is it?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling, yet still not breaking.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Hurt and putting on a brave face, yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am checking the shape of my soul.
ずっと...
Forever...
半端なら K.O.
Half-assed is K.O.
なんだかなってつまらないこともあるでしょう
There must be times when things feel boring and pointless, right?
ロンリー論理のノート ハンディー本気脱走
Lonely logic notebook, handicap, serious escape.
やんなっちゃって泥に Bad ご法度だろうが
Fed up, falling into bad mud, even if it's forbidden
溺れて堕ちて そろそろいっか
drown and fall into it, guess it's about time.
もっと頑張って 上がるまでもっと頑張って
Try harder, work harder until you get hyped.
繋がるよひとりよりふたり 増えたら安心 心配ないや
Connecting, two is better than one; with more people, no worries!
Alright 任せて Don't mind 波あり難題
Alright, leave it to me, Don't mind difficulties with waves.
みんなで乗っかっちゃえば 案外さくっと行っちゃいそう
If everyone hops on board, it'll go surprisingly smooth.
半端なら K.O. ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
Half-assed is K.O. If you want to float, go ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね ほら Say No 低音響かせ
Whether you cry or laugh, love me. Come on, Say No, let the bass resound.
今宵は暗転パーティー Woah
Tonight is a blackout party, Woah
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Dance, dance, solitude is sterilization, standing room only
痛みまで オシェアで ここらでバイバイ Let go
Even sharing the pain, bye-bye for now, Let go
どんな劣等感だって 即興の血小板で 抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞うんでしょ
No matter what inferiority complex, with improvisational platelets, hold it down, plunge in.
Up and down なテンション ねぇまいっちゃってんの相当
Up and down tension, I'm getting quite overwhelmed.
ドバッと噴き出すのは 本音の独り言
Gushing out all at once is the monologue of true feelings.
「別に興味ない」 「特に関係ない」
"Not particularly interested, has nothing to do with me."
塞ぎ込んで 舌鋒絶頂へ
Shutting oneself in, to the peak of sharp tongue.
合図を奏でて PrrPrrPrr
Play the signal, PrrPrrPrr.
ほら集まって夜行だぜ 鳴いていこう
Gather around, it's a night walk, let's howl out loud.
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Dance, dance, solitude is sterilization, standing room only
痛みまで オシェアで 今宵も暗転パーティーだ
Even sharing the pain, tonight is also a blackout party.
またねのお越しを きっと
Until your next visit, surely...
次回までお元気で ここらでバイバイ Let go
Until next time, stay well, bye-bye for now, Let go
胸ぐらを掴まれて 強烈なパンチを
Grabbed by the collar, taking an intense punch
食らってよろけて 肩を並べうずくまった
Staggering from it, crouching shoulder to shoulder.
予報通りの雨に お前はにやけて
You're grinning at the expected rain.
顔を上げて歩いていくには 太陽は眩し過ぎる
If you walk with your head held high, the sun is too dazzling.
下を向いて歩いていくには 人生は美し過ぎる
If you walk looking down, life is too beautiful.
絶望はこの雨のようなぬるい水だ 36度5分のユウウツだ
Despair is lukewarm water like this rain, a 36.5-degree melancholy.
傘も持たずに何処へいくって言うんだ
Where are you saying you're going without even an umbrella?
自分のために流す涙くらい汚いなんて言ってたくせに 君に別れを告げたあの夜
Even though you said shedding tears for yourself was dirty, on that night I said goodbye to you...
言葉が足りないのか 言葉じゃ足りないのか
Is it that words aren't enough? Or is it that words alone aren't enough?
本当は知っていたはずなのに
Even though I should have known the truth all along,
はずれた天気予報 雨、止みそうもない
a weather forecast that missed its mark, rain that shows no sign of stopping.
止まない雨は誰のものなの? 誰か教えて
Whose rain is this that won't stop? Someone tell me.
軽くだるく歩く奈落の底のような街で 後悔ばかりして生きている
Living with nothing but regrets in a town like the bottom of the abyss, walking lightly and sluggishly.
命なんて一人じゃ抱えきれないから 君に愛してるなんて言ったのか
Because life is too much to bear alone, did I say "I love you" to you?
激しくなる雨の音に掻き消される声
A voice drowned out by the sound of the intensifying rain.
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい 何度呟いても君は帰らない
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, no matter how many times I mutter it, you won't come back.
白い息に染まる公園通り 教会の鐘が鳴り響く
Park Avenue dyed in white breath, church bells ringing out.
幸せになってくれなんて嘘だ 不幸でもいいから傍にいてくれ
It's a lie to say "I hope you find happiness." I don't care if you're unhappy, just stay by my side.
はずれた天気予報 雨、止みそうもない 止まない雨は誰のものなの? 誰か教えて
A weather forecast that missed its mark, rain that shows no sign of stopping. Whose rain is this that won't stop? Someone tell me.
傘も持たずに何処へいくって言うんだ
Where are you saying you're going without even an umbrella?
自分のために流す涙くらい汚いなんて言ってたくせに
Even though you said shedding tears for yourself was dirty...
微温い優しさではなく 弱音に侵された 胸の奥を
Not lukewarm kindness, but digging into the depths of a chest invaded by cowardice...
抉るような言葉を
words that gouge deep.
何度も青アザだらけで涙を流して流して 不安定な心を肩に預け合いながら
Shedding tears over and over covered in blue bruises, while entrusting our unstable hearts to each other's shoulders...
腐り切ったバッドエンドに抗う買う
Fighting against a rotten bad end.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why is it? It feels more comfortable than joy.
痛みがずっしりと響いて
Pain echoes heavily and deeply,
濡れた服に 舌打ちしながら 腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
clicking my tongue at my soaked clothes, smiling as we look at our swollen faces.
土砂降りの夜に
On a torrential rainy night,
囚われの日々に
in these captive days,
問いかけるように
as if questioning,
光った瞳の中で
inside glistening eyes,
誓ったリベンジ
a sworn revenge.
深夜東京の6畳半 夢を見てた
Midnight in Tokyo, in a 6.5 tatami mat room, I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯 明日には消えている電脳城に
A fluorescent light that won't light up, in a cyber castle that will be gone by tomorrow.
開幕戦打ち上げていなくなんないよね
You won't blast off the opening match and disappear, right?
ここには誰もいない ここには誰もいないから
No one is here, because no one is here.
ここに救いはないよ 早く行っておいれ
There is no salvation here, hurry up and go on ahead.
難しい話はやめよう とりあえず上がって酒でも飲んでさ
Let's stop talking about difficult matters, come on up and have a drink or something.
いつも誰にでもいうことを
Repeating what I always say to anyone,
繰り返してる 完璧な演出と完璧な人生を
a flawless production and a flawless life.
幼期の面影は誰も知らないんだ
No one knows the shadows of my childhood.
誰もがマイノリティなタイムトラベラー ほら真夜中はすぐそこさ
Everyone is a minority time traveler, look, midnight is right around the corner.
深夜東京の6畳半 夢を見てた
Midnight in Tokyo, in a 6.5 tatami mat room, I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯 明日には消えている電脳城に
A fluorescent light that won't light up, in a cyber castle that will be gone by tomorrow.
開幕戦打ち上げていなくなんないよね
You won't blast off the opening match and disappear, right?
ここには誰もいない
No one is here.
明日は世界が終わるんだって
They say the world will end tomorrow,
昨日は眠れなくて
so I couldn't sleep yesterday.
小さな記憶の箱は 夜の海に浮かんでる
A small box of memories floats on the night sea.
僕らを描いたあの絵の中に 吸い込まれるように
As if being sucked into the painting of us.
終末旅行を楽しもう
Let's enjoy this end-of-the-world trip,
どうせ全部今日で終わりなんだから
since it's all ending today anyway.
深夜東京の6畳半 夢を見てた
In a six-mat room in midnight Tokyo, I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯 明日には消える電脳城に
Under a dim fluorescent light, in a cyber castle destined to vanish tomorrow,
開幕戦打ち上げて いなくなんないよね
we launched the opening battle—you won't disappear, right?
ここには誰もいない
No one is here.
深夜東京の6畳半 夢を見てた
In a six-mat room in midnight Tokyo, I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯 明日には消える電脳城に
Under a dim fluorescent light, in a cyber castle destined to vanish tomorrow,
開幕戦打ち上げて いなくなんないよね
we launched the opening battle—you won't disappear, right?
ここには誰もいないから
Because no one is here...
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
to the point of sleeplessness.
情熱の火はいつしか いつ日の日にか
The fire of passion, someday, on some day,
はなから気付いている 焔はいつか消える
I've known all along that the flame will eventually fade.
ねえ なにも要らないはずだった
Hey, I shouldn't have needed anything at all.
なのにまだ I'm so serious
Yet, I'm still so serious.
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, we can still make it in time.
ああ ただ burn it up
Ah, just burn it up.
Baby Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Baby, Sorry darling, it's not that sweet,
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
but I'm sure it's not that bad either.
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up Baby, let's burn it all down, yeah.
千代も八千代 変わりもせずに
Through eternity, unchanging,
全部燃やせ八百屋お七
burn it all down, Yaoya Oshichi.
出でよ舞えよ火の粉
Come forth, dance, sparks of fire.
焚き付けるのが仕事
Stoking the flames is my job.
ガソリンとサニタイズ 燃える様はお見事
Gasoline and sanitize, the burning sight is magnificent.
火遊びはしない
I won't play with fire,
ぬるいのも寝てたい
and I want to sleep off the lukewarm stuff.
しけたカルマ ドラマ燃やし尽くすマグマドラマ
A dreary karma drama, magma drama burning it all away.
この飽くなき渇き 青い炎みたい
This insatiable thirst is like a blue flame.
死は過去のひとつ隣 やがて全てひとつとなり
Death lies right next to the past, soon becoming one with everything.
Love is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
But since it hasn't faded yet,
忘れてみたい
I want to try forgetting.
情熱の火はいつしか いつ日の日にか
The fire of passion, someday, on some day,
身体は気づいている 僕らはいつか消える
My body realizes that we will eventually vanish.
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして
Gently dissolving my youth,
泣かないで Why so serious
don't cry, Why so serious.
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, we can still make it in time.
ああ ただ burn it up
Ah, just burn it up.
Baby Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Baby, Sorry darling, it's not that sweet,
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
but I'm sure it's not that bad either.
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up Baby, let's burn it all down, yeah.
Turn it up… 足りない 注ぐ火に油！
Turn it up... Not enough, pour oil on the fire!
Sorry darling Hurry up
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, we're still in time
Sorry darling Hurry up
あああ Burn it up
Ahh, burn it up
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up, baby, we're gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
現る黒い空
Dark skies emerge into view
鼓動は雷鳴を繰り返す
My heart thunders endlessly
嵐が来る前に
Before the storm comes
今宵はあの呪文を授けましょう
Tonight, I shall bestow that spell upon you
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
蘇らせるのさ
Reviving...
愛する君の心
The heart of the one you love
身体を脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off your body
今我に還るとき
Now is the time to return to me
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
天に吠えて 覚醒
Howl to the heavens, awaken!
目を瞑って
Close your eyes
風をすくって
Scoop up the wind
身を溶かして
Dissolve yourself
鐘を鳴らして
Ring the bells
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
天に吠えて 覚醒
Howl to the heavens, awaken!
雷鳴は何度もお産声をあげる
The thunder cries out once again
うたうのさ
I will sing
闇を越えて 飛び出せ
Beyond the darkness, fly away!
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガナシャラ
Amare dilahi, jumagi ganashara
マハリ ユワレ ガアイエ サヴァナレ
Mahari yuware, gaaie savanare
特報
[Special Report]
作詞 作曲
Lyrics / Music
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
編曲
Arrangement
Numa
オリジナル曲 制作決定
Original Song Production Decided
#天音かなた2周年LIVE
#AmaneKanata2ndAnniversaryLIVE
有象無象 人の成リ 虚勢 心象 人外 物の怪みたいだ
Like a monster born from the shapes and the shadows,
虚心坦懐 命宿し あとはぱっぱらぱんな中身なき人間
A hollow human left with a vacant heart and dictated fate,
寄せる期待 不平等な人生 才能もない 大乗 非日常が 怨親平等に没個性 辿る記憶 僕に 居場所などないから
Crying out with no place to belong in this unfair life.
夢の狭間で泣いてないで
Don't cry between the crevices of dreams,
どんな顔すればいいかわかってる
I know what kind of face I should make,
だけどまだ応えてくれよ
So give me an answer at last.
闇を祓って 闇を祓って
Exorcise the darkness, exorcise the darkness,
夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
Once the veil of darkness descends, that's our cue.
相対して 廻る環状戦 戯言などは 吐き捨ててゆけと
Leave all the nonsense and circular battles behind!
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで
Don't stop yet, don't stop yet!
誰よりも疼く 在る街に生まれし この正体を 今はただ
To search more keenly than anyone else for the truth in these streets,
呪い呪われた 僕の未来を創造して
Now let's imagine a cursed future of my own,
走って 転んで 消えない痛み抱いては
Running, falling, holding on to this unending pain,
世界が待ってる この一瞬を
The world is waiting for this very moment.
抒情的 感情が揺らいでいくバグ 従順に従った欠陥の罰
Bugs swaying tender emotions, punishment for submissive flaws,
死守選択しかない愛に無感覚 声も出せないまま
Deadly choices in indifferent love, unable to even make a sound.
傀儡な誓いのない百鬼夜行 数珠繋ぎなこの果てまでも
Night parade of oathless puppets, to the very end of hell.
極楽往生 現実蹴って凪いで 命を投げ出さないで
Paradise rebirth, kicking reality away, don't throw your life away!
内の脆さに浸って どんな顔すればいいかわからないよ
Wallowing in inner weakness, not knowing what face to make,
今はただ 応えてくれよ
Give me an answer now!
五常を解いて 五常を解いて
解いて、五常を解いて
不確かな声を紡ぐアイデア
An idea weaving uncertain voices together.
相殺して 廻る感情線 その先に今 立ち上がる手を
Killing each other in an emotional loop, raising our hands to the future.
ただ追いかけて ただ追いかけて
Just keep chasing, just keep chasing!
誰よりも強く 在りたいと願う 君の運命すらいまはただ
Wishing to be stronger than anyone, your fate is just that—
灰暗い夜の底に 深く深く落ちこんで 不格好に見えたかい これが今の僕なんだ
Falling deep into the dark night, look, this is the pathetic me.
何者にもなれないだけの屍だ 吠えろよ
Just a corpse that could become nothing, go on and laugh!
目の前の全てから 逃げることさえやめた
Giving up even on running away from everything in front of me,
イメージを繰り返し 想像の先をいけと
Repeating the imagery, go beyond imagination!
闇を祓って 闇を祓って
Exorcise the darkness, exorcise the darkness,
夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
Once the veil of darkness descends, that's our cue.
相対して 廻る環状戦 戯言などは 吐き捨ててゆけと
Leave all the nonsense and circular battles behind!
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで
Don't stop yet, don't stop yet!
誰よりも疼く 在る街に生まれし この正体を 今はただ
To search more keenly than anyone else for the truth in these streets,
呪い呪われた 僕の未来を創造して
Now let's imagine a cursed future of my own,
走って 転んで 消えない痛み抱いては
Running, falling, holding on to this unending pain,
世界が待ってる この一瞬を
The world is waiting for this very moment.
咽び、いつもの様に 過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Sighing, like every day, a yawn slips out into passing days.
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も 渋谷の街に朝が降る
A bustling night passes, and morning falls on Shibuya's streets today too.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち つまらないな
Such a hollow feeling, how boring.
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ これでいい
But that's fine, yeah, something like that is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を押してよ、ほら
Let your true voice ring out, the one you've kept hidden away!
見ないふりしていても 確かにそこにある
Even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely there.
呼呼、いつもの様に 過ぎる日々にあくが出る
Ah, another day passes by with a yawn,
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
crossing over the bustling night, today too
渋谷の街に朝が降りる
morning descends on the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち
A somewhat hollow feeling inside,
つまらないな でもそれでいい
"How boring," but that's fine,
そんなもんだ これでいい
that's just how it is, this is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hiding away
本当の声を聞かせてよ、ほら
the true voice inside you, come on,
見ないフリしていても
even if you pretend not to see it,
確実にあるから
it is definitely right there.
呼呼、手を伸ばせば 伸ばすほどに
Ah, the more that I reach out my hands,
遠くへゆく
the further away they go.
思うようにいかない、今日も
Things don't go as I wish today either,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
as I struggle in a hurried frenzy once more.
悔しい気持ちも ただ情けなくて
Feelings of frustration and sheer helplessness
涙が出る
bring tears to my eyes.
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる
The deeper I step in, the more painful it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more it hurts.
感じたままに進む 自分で選んだこの道を
Moving as I feel, down this path I chose myself,
重いまぶた擦る夜に
on a night rubbing my heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung tightly to a blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what you love—
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
it's not just all fun and games.
本当にできる? 不安になるけど
"Can I really do this?" Though doubts creep in,
何枚でも ほら何枚でも
time and time again, look, page after page,
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I kept drawing because I lacked confidence.
何回でも ほら何回でも
Time and time again, look, trial after trial,
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
everything I've piled up becomes my weapon.
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
No matter who I look at or compare myself to,
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is the one thing only I can do?
今でも自信なんかない それでも
Even now I have no confidence, yet even so...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い
Feelings I've never felt, emotions I didn't know—
あの日踏み出して 初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
stepping out that day, even all this pain I felt for the first time.
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing what I love,
触れた まだ小さな光
I touched a light, still so small.
大丈夫、行こう、あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy it!
全てを賭けて描く 自分にしか出せない色で
Drawing with my all, in colors only I can express,
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
running through dawn and night, I found the blue light.
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing what you love
今だって怖いことだけど
is still a terrifying thing,
もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
but I am no longer that transparent self of that day—
かけがえのない僕だ
I am irreplaceable.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を押せよ、ほら
Let the true voice you've hidden away resonate, come on!
見ないフリしていても 確実にそこにあるよ
Even if you pretend not to see it, it is definitely right there.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を押せよ、さあ
Let the true voice you've hidden away resonate, now!
見ないフリしていても 確実にそこにある 君の中に
Even if you pretend not to see it, it is definitely right inside you.
Don't take your love away, You ain't heard nothin' yet-yet
Don't take your love away, Wake up, make up, bang bang
また鳴り出した表示はあなた「今忙しいの」
The notification pops up again: "I'm busy right now."
未読のトークとラブコールもいっぱいで忙しい、「邪魔をしないで頂戴」
Unread chats and love calls pile up—"Don't get in my way!"
Cuz you refuse cooperation, better stick out your lip. Too used to sayin' "I don't wanna", no doubt you're still a kid
本音は言わない方が悩ましい
It's more troubling when you hide your true feelings,
甘い言葉かけるよりもずっと愛しい
and far more endearing than sweet words.
たまらなくなるほど 求めて離さないで
Craving you so much it drives me crazy, hold me tight and never let go.
キスじゃ足りなくて いっそ殺して
A kiss isn't enough, just kill me instead.
Predilection あなたを手にかけて
Predilection, taking you into my hands,
Infatuation 呼吸さえしとめて
Infatuation, stopping even your breath,
Dedication このまま
Dedication, just like this,
Addiction してまだ たった一口で「終わり」
Addiction, ending with just a single bite.
Predilection さあさ口をつけて
Predilection, come on, put your lips to mine,
Infatuation そのまま飲み込んで
Infatuation, swallow me down just as I am,
Dedication すぐさま
Dedication, right away,
Addiction してほら たった一口「死ぬほど」愛したいから
Addiction, because I want to love you to death with just one bite.
Don't take your love away, You ain't heard nothin' yet-yet
Don't take your love away, Wake up, make up, bang bang
Uh, have it all, like it love is overflowing
Be the only one you got, I don't think you'll be going, going
Uh, take it off, still it's not enough for me, Stuck. With. You. There's no room for other things.
胸を刺した この手掴んだ
Stabbing my chest, I grabbed this hand.
まだ視線があるのね
You're still looking at me, aren't you?
あああなたわ ワガママ
Ah, you are so selfish.
愛と名付けてまた支配する
Naming it love, you dominate me again.
あなたに溺れてく 息苦しくらいに
Drowning in you, to the point of suffocation.
深酔いそうそうと急上昇して
Getting overly drunk and rapidly rising up.
私を手にかけて
Take my life into your hands
キスで口塞いで
And seal my lips with a kiss.
知てんだずっと 非情に好きよ
I've always known, I love you ruthlessly.
咽流し込んで 届くなら仕込んで
Swallowing it down, if it reaches you, train me.
邪魔だ今のは捨てて
Throw away what's in the way now.
すぐさま 知てまった 一口これで終わらせないで
Realizing it instantly, don't let it end with just one bite.
Our loves, loves continue to further evolve more.
My love love is besotted with you.
You love? love? continue to further evolve mo-mo-more!
I'm a little confused.
You already know it, love is war.
What you gotta act righteous for?
Won't ya come and fight me? Shit, Aphrodite was supposed to only wanna be adored.
You can ditch your world. Cuz I'm all you need.
With those wild words, I fall to my knees.
In the end, the reason isn't hard to see.
Understanding "love," it just ain't for me.
たまに苦しくなるほど 求め手離さないで
To the point of occasional pain, seek me and don't let me go.
キスじゃ足りなくていっそ殺して
A kiss isn't enough, just kill me instead.
あなたを手にかけて
Take my life into your hands
呼吸さえしてとめて
And even stop my breath.
このまま 知てんだずっと 非情に好きよ
Staying like this, I've always known, I love you ruthlessly.
さあさあ 口をつけて そのまま飲み込んで
Come on, put your lips to mine and swallow it down as is.
邪魔だ今のは捨てて すぐさま
Throw away what's in the way now, immediately.
さよなら真っ赤 吐き出して 息が止まるのよ今
Goodbye, bright red, spit it out, my breath stops right now.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me
はるか遠い遠い昔 巻かれた首輪は
A long, long time ago, far away, the wrapped collar...
人が欲しい 人が欲しい と叫ぶ 呪いの首輪
Is a cursed collar crying out 'I want people, I want people.'
怒らないで 見捨てないで どこも行かないで
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere.
強く締める 吐くまで締める 人がいないいないと いい成績でしょ
Tightening strongly, tightening until I vomit, that there are no people is a good result, right?
ねぇ ねぇ 良い子でしょう 可愛い子でしょう ねぇ ねぇ 良い子でしょう 苦しいね
Hey, hey, aren't I a good child? A cute child? Hey, hey, aren't I a good child? It hurts, doesn't it?
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと 愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, love me, more and more, love me, love me, until it drives me crazy.
苦しい 苦しい 呪縛を 解いて 解いて ねぇ
It hurts, it hurts, please break the curse, break it, hey.
止められない
I can't stop it.
身体 身体 大きくなっても 小さい首輪は
Even if your body grows big, the small collar...
苦しくなる 足りなくなる 人が 人が 足りない
Becomes painful, not enough, people, people are not enough.
クラスの誰にも負けない キレイな子でしょう
I'm a pretty child who won't lose to anyone in class, right?
あの子よりもどの子よりも 誰も彼も私を見てよ
More than that girl, more than any girl, everyone, everyone, look at me.
体育館裏 あなたに告白を 嘘みたいでしょ あなたが好きなの
Behind the gymnasium, a confession to you. Sounds like a lie, right? I love you.
汚いあなたが
Your dirty self...
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部あげる あなたに あなたに 全部背負ってもらうよ
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything. You will carry everything on you.
りない あなたが 足りない 離さないよ
Not enough, you are not enough, I won't let go.
離さないよ 鳴呼
I won't let go, ah...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっともっと
more and more!
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっともっと
more and more!
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, to the point of madness!
苦しい 本当に
It hurts, truly,
苦しい 離さない
it hurts, I won't let go.
苦しい もっともっと ねぇ
It hurts, more and more, hey...
幸せなの
Is this happiness...
幸せなのかなぁ
...is this what happiness is?
あたしが愛を語るのなら
If I were to speak of love,
その眼には如何、写る？
how would it reflect in those eyes?
詞は有り余るばかり
Words are nothing but excess,
無垢の音が流れてく
as innocent sounds flow on.
あなたが愛にまみれるまで
Until you are stained with love,
その色は幻だ
that color is just an illusion.
ひとりぼっち 音に呑まれれば
If you're swallowed up by the sound all alone,
全世界共通の快楽さ
it's a universal pleasure across the world.
つまらない茫然に溺れる暮らし
A boring life sinking into vague blankness,
誰もが彼をなぞる
everyone traces his footsteps.
繰り返す使い回しの歌にまた耳を塞いだ
I plugged my ears once again to the repetitive, recycled song.
あなたが愛を語るのならそれを答とするの？
If you speak of love, is that your answer?
目ををつぶったふりをしているならこの曲で醒ましてくれ！
If you're pretending to close your eyes, wake up with this song!
誰も知らぬ物語 想うばかり
Thinking only of a story nobody knows,
壊れそうなくらいに抱き締めて泣き踊った
I hugged myself tight enough to break and danced while crying.
見境無い感情論 許されるのならば 泣き出すことすらできないまま呑み込んでった
Indiscriminate emotionalism—if I'm forgiven, I swallowed it all down without even being able to cry.
張り裂けてしまいそうな心があるってこと、叫ばせて！
Let me scream that I have a heart on the verge of bursting!
世界があたしを拒んでも 今、愛の唄歌わせてくれないかな
Even if the world rejects me, won't you let me sing a song of love right now?
もう一回 誰も知らないその想い この声に預けてみてもいいかな
Once more, can I entrust this unknown feeling to this voice?
あなたには僕が見えるか？ あなたには僕が見えるか？
Can you see me? Can you see me?
ガラクタばかり投げつけられてきたその背中
That back, onto which only junk was thrown,
それでも好きと言えたなら それでも好きを願えたら
if I could still say I love you, if I could still wish for love—
ああ、あたしの全部にその意味はあると
Ah, that my entire existence has meaning.
ねぇ、愛を語るのなら 今その胸には誰がいる
Hey, if you speak of love, who is in your heart right now?
こころのはこを抉じ開けて さあ、生写しのあなた見せて？
Pry open the box of your heart and show me your living reflection.
あたしが愛になれるのなら 今その色は何色だ
If I can become love, what color is that color right now?
孤独なんて記号では収まらない 心臓を抱えて生きてきたんだ！
Loneliness can't be contained by mere symbols; I've lived holding my beating heart!
ドッペルもどきが其処処に溢れた 挙句の果ての今日
Doppelganger-like things overflowed everywhere, leading to today.
ライラ ライ ライ 心失きそれを生み出した奴等は 見切りをつけてもう バイ バイ バイ
Laira-li-li, those who created that heartless thing have given up and said bye-bye-bye.
残されたあなたがこの場所で今でも 涙を堪えてるのどうして、どうして
You, left behind, are still holding back tears in this place—why, oh why?
あたしは知ってるわ この場所はいつでも あなたに守られてきたってこと！
I know! This place has always been protected by you!
痛みなどあまりにも慣れてしまった
I've grown far too used to the pain.
何千回と巡らせ続けた 喜怒と哀楽
The joy, anger, sorrow, and pleasure that I made cycle thousands of times.
失えない喜びがこの世界にあるならば 手放すことすらできない悲しみさえあたしは
If there is an irreplaceable joy in this world, even the sadness I can't let go of—
この心の中 つまはじきにしてしまうのか？ それは、いやだ！
will I end up casting it out from my heart? No, I refuse that!
どうやって この世界を愛せるかな いつだって 転がり続けるんだろう
How can I ever love this world? I'll probably just keep stumbling on forever.
ねぇ、いっそ誰も気づかないその想い この唄で明かしてみようと思うんだよ
Hey, I think I'll try revealing that feeling, which no one notices, through this song.
あなたが何を願うか あなたが何を望むか 刻んだ心が誰より今を生きてるの
Whatever you wish for, whatever you desire, the heart engraved within lives in the present more than anyone.
あなたには僕が見えるか？ あなたには僕が見えるか？ それ、あたしの行く末を照らす灯火なんだろう？
Can you see me? Can you see me? Surely that must be the light illuminating my future path, right?
ねぇ、あいをとさけぶのなら
Hey, if you're going to shout of love,
あたしはここにいるよ ことばがありあまるほど この夢はつづいてく
I'm right here with more than enough words, this dream continues.
あたしが愛を語るのなら そのすべてはこの歌だ
If I were to speak of love, all of it would be this song.
誰も知らないこの物語 またクチーズさんでしまったみたいだ
This story nobody knows, looks like I got choked up again.
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
揺るがない世界 非情な現状
An unwavering world, a merciless current situation
続く壁は何重層？
How many layers of walls continue?
イメージ通りなんかじゃない
It's not at all what I imagined
静かに騒ぎだした本能
An instinct that began to stir quietly
迷いみたい 行き止まりなんだ
Like a maze, it's a dead end
もう思考はディストーション
My thoughts are already a distortion
容赦ないね いつの間に
So merciless, before I knew it
見失ったルート、暴れだす
The lost route starts to rage
Pay attention!
Hey what is it?
Watch your step now! 常識なんか要らない
Watch your step now! I don't need common sense
Are you serious!? No no no, don't worry 1, 2, 3
吹き返す 心臓のリズム
The rhythm of the heart revives
視界まだ眩んでる それでも行かなくちゃ
My vision is still dazzled, but I still have to go
キミが信じてる僕を 裏切るわけにいかない
I can't betray you who believes in me
強くクラクションが鳴る
A car horn blares loudly
孤独なまま時が経ったって
Even if time passes in solitude
逃げる事覚えたって
Even if I learned how to run away
新しい今日が来ちゃうけど
A new today will come anyway
この願い 例え魔法が無なくたって
Even if this wish has no magic
叶えなきゃ、誓った
I swore I had to make it come true
僕はキミと まだ見たい未来 あるんだよ
I still want to see a future with you
泣きそうでも 悔しくても止まっていられない
Even if I feel like crying, even if I feel frustrated, I can't stop
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
デモ・ケドnonstepでガンガン迫るhard way
But still, non-stop, approaching hard way
Where's the solution!?
打ちのめされても get up!
Even if beaten down, get up!
Come on! Hurry up!
そんな損な時間ならすぐさまゴミ箱
Trash such a wasteful time instantly
後悔なんて塵埃同然
Regrets are mere dust
さぁ2 step OK shouting OK 欲張り遊ばせ
Now 2 step OK shouting OK, play greedily
可否も賛否も全部僕のもの 飛ばせ 心臓のアルゴリズム
Both pros and cons are entirely mine, make the algorithm of the heart fly
ほら 守りたいんだって僕の声が伝播した
Hey, I wanted to protect it, my voice transmitted
異論反論は許すけど この想いは不用意に科学できないでしょう？
I'll forgive objections and counterarguments, but you couldn't casually scientize this feeling, could you?
聞いてよ 辿り着いた正解 言わなくちゃ
Listen, I must say the correct answer I reached
キミがくれる想いの 全部を信じていける
I can believe in all the feelings you give me
それが嘘かどうかなんて わからなくてもいい
It doesn't matter if I don't know whether it's a lie or not
誰かが示す見本ってなんだっけ 普通の愛ってなんだっけ 僕は今日も僕に問いかける
What was the model shown by someone again? What was ordinary love again? I question myself today as well
問いかける度 手に入れるのは 変わらない真実
Every time I question, what I get is the unchanging truth
「僕は要らない まだ見たい未来があるから」
"I don't need it because there's a future I still want to see"
孤独なんかは消えて無くなって 逃げる事嫌になって
Solitude disappears completely, hating to run away
新しい今日を探すんだよ
I'll search for a new today
この願い 例え魔法が無なくたって
Even if this wish has no magic
叶えなきゃ、誓った
I swore I had to make it come true
僕とキミで創れる未来ならもう近い
The future we can create together is already close
僕の右手 キミの左手 そっと繋いで
My right hand and your left hand, gently holding together
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
離さないから that's rising hope
Because I won't let go, that's rising hope
rising hope
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキッスで”
My repayment is a love-filled flying kiss!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ♥
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って 恋しちゃって下さい！
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること なんでもします
I'll do whatever it takes!
NG無しで 体当たり挑戦
Tackling everything head-on without holding back!
エゴサで見つけた アンチのコメ
The anti's comments I found from ego-searching,
ふざけんな…
Don't mess with me...
誰より分かってるし
I understand that better than anyone,
でも大丈夫 ここに立てば みんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on this stage, everyone's here.
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキッスで”
My repayment is a love-filled flying kiss!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll make you captive! More! Show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves, a love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物ににします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
Scandals are still too early, but
裏切りません！宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I'm declaring that right now.
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with pure skill!
だから辞めない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
That's why I won't quit, I hate losing, and I'm right here!
拳あげるて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった mona ビームで”
My repayment is with a love-filled Mona beam!
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Loud cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept it, my love-filled selfish song!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is drawing near, it's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？(約束！)
We'll meet again and again, right? (Promise!)
優しさに溢れている言葉も 心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Even words overflowing with kindness, even the heartless words of someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強くなろう
They're necessary. Let's grow strong!
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Scream as you like! More! Enjoy yourselves! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so that this will be a special day.
共に歌おうずーっと！共に歩もうずーっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉はとびっきりのL・O・V・E
Our password is a sparkling L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキッスで”
My repayment is a love-filled flying kiss!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll make you captive! More! Show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves, a love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
みんなのおかげで 歌うことができました 本当に本当にみんなのことが大好きだよ！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to sing. I truly, truly love you all!
優しく鐘の音鳴って
Gently, the sound of a bell tolls,
永久にじゃれあいタイな
I want to playfully frolic forever.
鳥籠いらない そんな理想に満ちた此処へ
To a place filled with ideals where no birdcage is needed—
君を連れ出せたなら
if I could take you away there.
ねぇ羽の色も髪の色も 違ってそれぞれ綺麗
Hey, the color of our wings and hair are different, yet each is beautiful.
傷付かないように包み込もう
Let's embrace so as not to get hurt.
守ってたら守られてた 君へのこの讃歌
Protecting you, I was protected. This hymn of praise to you,
ずっと届けよう
I will always deliver.
さぁ祝福を
Now, let's bestow our blessing!
ファミリア 癒して 束の間嬉しい幸せ
Familia, heal us for a brief, happy moment.
寄り添って 辛さ全部おおのてめで
Snuggling close, covering up all our hardships.
ファミリア 誰にも 見せない表情を
Familia, a facial expression shown to no one,
羽の奥からそっと 僕だけへと
gently from deep within my wings, just for me.
飛んで 飛んで 舞い降りる 天使のagape
Fly, fly, and dance down, O angel's agape.
弱さを見せてもいいよ
It's okay to show your weakness.
辛さ押し付けていいよ
It's okay to push your hardships onto me.
例え離れたとしても 空からの使いだから
Even if we are separated, as a messenger from the sky,
君を見守るんだ
I will watch over you.
ねぇ出会えたこと 笑えたこと その先で報われて
Hey, meeting you, being able to smile—rewarded beyond that,
幸せ更に重ね合わせよう
let's pile happiness even higher together.
大切なものがある聖域 役目を刻み込んで
A sanctuary with what is precious, carving our roles into it,
きっと誰にも きっと譲らない
surely to no one will we ever yield.
白く広く 白く羽ばたく
White and wide, fluttering white...
白く白く 白く白く
White, white, white, white...
ファミリア 癒して 束の間嬉しい幸せ
Familia, heal us for a brief, happy moment.
寄り添って 辛さ全部おおのてめで
Snuggling close, covering up all our hardships.
ファミリア 誰にも 見せない表情を
Familia, a facial expression shown to no one,
羽の奥からそっと 僕だけへと
gently from deep within my wings, just for me.
飛んで 飛んで 舞い降りる 天使のagape
Fly, fly, and dance down, O angel's agape.
いつでもここにいるよ
I will always be right here.
特者生存ワンダラダー!!
Survival of the fittest, Wonder-la-der!!
なぬっ!? ビシッ おりゃっ! バシッ ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
What?! Wham, take this! Wham! My comebacks are sharp, today is clear skies!
さわっ ボロ… ぎゅむ バキッ 手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれ
Touch, tattered... squeak, snap! Everything I get is mine! Gimme!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか?) そんなんだっていいけどさ
Let's do our best moderately (Is that so?) Even if it's like that,
必死にがんばろっか (そうだな!) それが僕らしいよな
let's do our best desperately (That's right!) That's so like me, isn't it?
ダサすぎじゃねえんだわ! そんで貧乏っちいじゃねえんだわ!
It's not that I'm too uncool! And it's not that I'm shabby!
うん! 万事がバッチリ イケてるに決まってる!
Yup! Everything's totally going well, obviously!
(are you?) かなたちゃん☆ どどん! 前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して
(Are you?) Kanata-chan☆ Full speed ahead! Welcome us properly,
高まれ 海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して 興奮しよう
rise high, create sea and sky, be amazed properly, let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Since I'm saying it, I'm gonna make it real!
現実超える未来あー!
A future transcending reality, ah—!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー!
Weaknesses are fine too, launcher with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダーDAY楽しもう
In other words, survival of the fittest Wonder-la-der DAY, let's enjoy it!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダDAY 楽しもう
Survival of the Fittest Wonderada DAY! Let's have fun!
面白がれること探したまえ、over?
Go seek out things you can enjoy, over?
返事聞かせてくれ！
Let me hear your reply!
右左なんかじゃない
It's not about left or right,
決めつけて一直線
I set my sights straight ahead!
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ
Once I scheme it, launch is all clear!
ワクワクすんぜ！しゃ──！
I'm getting so excited! Yeah!
みんな！2年目突入しましたが、まだ実感が湧いてません！
Everyone! We've entered our 2nd year, but it still hasn't really sunk in!
2年目の目標はハイアップはついたオリジナル曲を出すこと！
My 2nd-year goal is to release original songs with hype!
「なんだよそんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おばか！」
"What's that? You shouldn't say stuff like that, dummy!"
「うわ～すごい！ありがと～」
"Whoa, amazing! Thank you so much!"
日々これ騒乱でgo my way!
Day in, day out, going my way in chaos!
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん だって意気ガンガンがいいんだもん
I want to remain vigilant, because gung-ho spirit is best!
全方位にがっつりアンテナ張っていなくちゃ！
I've got to keep my antennas fully up in every direction!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋でいたいな
No matter when, I want my heart to stay pure and true,
好奇心は絶えず熱心でいたいなって言いたいなんて
wanting to keep my curiosity burning bright forever...
言い聞かせるんだ 調子に乗ったら
I keep telling myself. If I get carried away,
すぐ飽きられちゃうからあー！
people will get bored of me right away—aah!
タイトなロープもっとこいってばよ
Bring on an even tighter rope!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダDAY
Namely, Survival of the Fittest Wonderada DAY!
しがみつけ“努力とは最後まで諦めないこと”メモっておいて！
Hang on tight—"Effort means never giving up until the very end"—remember that!
ホントはbaby 自信なんかないよ
The truth is, baby, I don't have any confidence.
ホントはbaby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだ
The truth is, baby, I'm full of anxiety and about to cry.
でもねbaby 挫けないって決めたの だからbaby
But you know, baby, I decided not to break, so baby,
挑戦したいよ 未開の天地 無限のフィールドで！
I want to take on the challenge in an uncharted realm, on an infinite field!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して 高まれ
Advance is top-notch! Welcome it properly and let your spirits soar!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して 興奮しよう
Create seas and skies, be amazed properly, and get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Since I'm saying it, I'm really going to make it happen!
現実超える未来あー！
A future that transcends reality—aah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Flaws are fine too, launcher with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダDAY
Namely, Survival of the Fittest Wonderada DAY!
楽しもう 面白がれること探し放題でっせ
Let's enjoy ourselves! It's an all-you-can-find feast of fun things!
無限のフィールドで
On this infinite field,
タイミング失くしてもいい
even if I miss the timing, it's okay!
真ん中一直線
Straight down the middle!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ 胸を張れ！
In short, this is my answer. Stick your chest out!
今を生きるその意味を 明く日も明る来る日も確かめ進め！
Verify the meaning of living in the present, and keep advancing through bright days and brighter days!
わーりゃー！
Waryaa!
天音かなた2周年記念ライブ「リベンジ」どうだったでしょうか？
How was Amane Kanata's 2nd Anniversary Live "Revenge"?
本日一番印象に残った曲はどれだったでしょうか？
Which song left the strongest impression on you today?
こちらセットリストになっているんですが、1とか2とか3とかね、曲名の前にある数字を大文字でも小文字でもOKなので、コメントに言ってくれると...
This is the setlist right here, and if you could comment the number in front of the song title—uppercase or lowercase is fine—...
え、勝手に機械が集計いたします。これの集計結果は配信後に僕のTwitterアカウントで発表したいと思います。みんなありがとうございます！
Um, the machine will automatically tally them up. I'd like to announce the results on my Twitter account after the stream. Thank you everyone!
そして、じゃかじゃかじゃん！どどん！活動2周年記念グッズ、もーもーぼんぼん、ばんばん、こちらもね今回出させていただきまーす！
And then, ta-da! Boom! The 2nd Anniversary commemorative merch—moo-moo, bon-bon, bam-bam—we're releasing this as well this time!
え、直筆サインも書くのでぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。え、まずは紹介してきたと思います。
Um, I'll also be writing handwritten signatures, so please be sure to check it out. Um, I'll introduce them first.
あ、えっと、アンケートの方はね、引き続き集計中ですので、あの数字ね打っていただけると嬉しいです。はい、まずはラバーマット、にまし先生に書いていただきました！
Oh, um, as for the questionnaire, it's still being tallied, so I'd be happy if you could enter the number. Right, first is the rubber mat, illustrated by Nimashi-sensei!
可愛い。そして手帳型マルチスマホケース、スマホケースみんな欲しいて言ってたので作ったぞと。
So cute. And the tech-style multi smartphone case—everyone said they wanted a smartphone case, so I made it!
そして、天音かなた1stシングル『特者生存ワンダラダ！！』
And, Amane Kanata's 1st Single "Tokusha Seizon Wonderer!!"
そして、2ndシングルの『天使のagape』こちらもブルーダッパーをカバーさせていただきましたので、ぜひぜひそっちもチェックしてほしいなと思います。
And, the 2nd single "Tenshi no agape"—we also covered Blue Clapper for this, so I really hope you check that out too.
ということですね、みなさん本当にたくさんありがとうございます。コメントもありがとう。そしてそしてこちらね、活動2周年記念のねグッズのこちらね構成、構成になっております。
With that said, everyone, thank you so much. Thanks for the comments too. And here is the composition of the 2nd anniversary merch.
ボイスもね取りました。なんか罵倒系のねボイスをとったのでぜひそちらもチェックしてみてください、Vの皆さんは。はい！
I also recorded voice packs. I recorded some scolding-type voice packs, so please check those out too, VTubers! Yes!
そして『天使のagape』ですが、こちらの楽曲の配信は昨日の夜から始まっておりますので
And as for "Tenshi no agape", distribution for this song started last night, so...
まずはぜひチェックしてみてください。
First of all, please be sure to check it out.
そしてこのあとすぐ、22時15分から
And right after this at 10:15 PM,
アニメMVが投稿されるので、
the anime MV will be posted,
かなたのチャンネルにそのまま座っていてください。
so please stay seated on Kanata's channel.
ぜひぜひチェックしてみてね、ということで
Be sure to check it out! So,
皆さん今回は本当に本当に、ありがとうございました！
everyone, thank you so, so much this time!
天音かなた二周年、そして三周年に
Entering Amane Kanata's 2nd and 3rd anniversary,
入りまして、三年目か、三年目に入りまして、
well, going into our 3rd year,
これからも元気いっぱいがんばっていきたいと思います！
I'll keep doing my absolute best with full energy!
それでは、おつかなたでしたー！
With that, Otsukanata!
バイバーイ、ありがとう！
Bye-bye, thank you!